const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the dermatome that is involved in referring the pain from the appendix to the umbilical region?","answers":[{"option":"10th thoracic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"3rd cervical nerve","bool":false},{"option":"5th cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"7th thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"4th thoracic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is recommended for the quickest treatment for ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"Omeprazole","bool":true},{"option":"H2 antagonists","bool":false},{"option":"Misoprostol","bool":false},{"option":"Antacid","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"The Rule of Nines is used for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Head trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Burns","bool":true},{"option":"Fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Electrical injury","bool":false},{"option":"Datura poisoning","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Encephalopathy, wrist-drop, and constipation are the triad most commonly seen in which of the following toxicities?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphorous","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Thallium","bool":false},{"option":"Mercury","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is characterized by recurrent aphthous ulcers?","answers":[{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false},{"option":"Irritable bowel syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn's disease","bool":true},{"option":"Giardiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is most commonly associated with a tumor in the head of the pancreas?","answers":[{"option":"Epigastric discomfort","bool":false},{"option":"Dark urine","bool":false},{"option":"Nausea and vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive jaundice","bool":true},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which organ produces the most digestive enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":true},{"option":"Small intestines","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Salivary glands","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the pancreas?","answers":[{"option":"Its neck, body and tail develops from the ventral bud","bool":false},{"option":"It is mesodermal in origin","bool":false},{"option":"It is the embryonic derivative of foregut","bool":true},{"option":"Its uncinate process develops from the dorsal bud","bool":false},{"option":"It is ectodermal in origin","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of esophageal variceal bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"Wilson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cirrhosis","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty liver","bool":false},{"option":"Schistosomiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following will be observed on endoscopic biopsy of celiac disease?","answers":[{"option":"Dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Aplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Villous atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Metaplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following results from the first hit in the pathogenesis of colorectal carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Methylation instability","bool":false},{"option":"Chromosomal alteration","bool":false},{"option":"Germline and somatic mutations of tumor suppressor genes","bool":true},{"option":"Protooncogene mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Upregulation of COX 1","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 35-year-old female patient reports having epigastric abdominal pain for the last 7 months and has also lost 10 kg weight during this time. She is currently taking proton pump inhibitors (PPI). What is the next step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Continue proton pump inhibitors (PPI)","bool":false},{"option":"Stool culture","bool":false},{"option":"Order an endoscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Stop all medication","bool":false},{"option":"Test for Helicobacter pylori","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is used to screen for colorectal carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor markers assessment","bool":false},{"option":"Colonoscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT) scan","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 37-year-old patient, on steroids for ulcerative colitis, is in sustained remission. He develops central obesity and a moon-like face. What is the next step in his management?","answers":[{"option":"Continue steroids for remission","bool":false},{"option":"Ileal resection","bool":false},{"option":"Proctocolectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Treat Cushing’s syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a complication of acute liver failure?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Cerebral edema","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalopathy","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which disease does not cause cholestatic jaundice?","answers":[{"option":"Zellweger syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hodgkin disease","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":true},{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following signs can help confirm appendicitis?","answers":[{"option":"Trousseau sign","bool":false},{"option":"Cullen’s sign","bool":false},{"option":"Grey Turner’s sign","bool":false},{"option":"Psoas sign","bool":true},{"option":"Troisier’s sign","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 21-year-old female presents to the emergency room in an unconscious state. On examination, she has a sweet-smelling odor. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lactic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alklaosis","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the most common site of diverticulitis?","answers":[{"option":"Descending colon","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse colon","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid colon","bool":true},{"option":"Ascending colon","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 38-year-old woman presents with weight loss, evening pyrexia, night sweats. On examination, she has a lump in the right quadrant. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Colorectal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn disease","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the most common site of Intestinal tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"1st part of the duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"2st part of the duodenum","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal ileum","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal ileum","bool":true},{"option":"3st part of the duodenum","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a polypoid bulge of the mucosa of the large bowel that is present in ulcerative colitis?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperplastic polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudopolyp","bool":true},{"option":"Inflammatory polyp","bool":false},{"option":"Adenomatous polyp","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following parameters help differentiate between cholelithiasis and acute cholecystitis?","answers":[{"option":"Platelet count","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocyte count","bool":true},{"option":"Epigastric pain","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocyte count","bool":false},{"option":"Jaundice","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a sign of localized peritonitis?","answers":[{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Rebound tenderness on affected area","bool":true},{"option":"Irregular pulse","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of abdominal movement during respiration","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is characterized by subtotal villous atrophy?","answers":[{"option":"Gastroenteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Irritable bowel syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn disease","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Parietal cell antibodies are present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Colorectal carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic gastritis","bool":true},{"option":"Crohn disease","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 39-year-old female comes to the outpatient department with abdominal pain. She has a history of weight loss and jaundice. Labs reveal raised alpha-fetoprotein (AFP) and des-gamma-carboxyprothrombin (DCP) levels. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatic adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cirrhosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cholangiocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Primary hepatic lymphoma","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Adenocarcinoma is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Gasrtoenteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic megacolon","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Ulcerative colitis","bool":true},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the name of the sign in which right inferior quadrant (RIQ) pain is elicited by palpation of the left inferior quadrant (LIQ)?","answers":[{"option":"McBurney's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Dunphy's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator sign","bool":false},{"option":"Rovsing's sign","bool":true},{"option":"Psoas sign","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with a low-fiber diet?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic bowel","bool":false},{"option":"Crohn’s disease","bool":false},{"option":"Colon carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Acute gastritis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) levels are raised in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Metastatic colorectal cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Mucoepidermoid carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A man at a barbeque party starts vomiting profusely and continuously. He also complains of lower chest and upper abdominal pain, He is taken to the hospital. On examination, tenderness, tachycardia, and hypotension are observed. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Acute gastritis","bool":false},{"option":"Boerhaave syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the most common site of colorectal carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Sigmoid colon","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending colon","bool":false},{"option":"Descending colon","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":true},{"option":"Ileocecal junction","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A portocaval anastomosis does not lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Encephalopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Variceal bleeding","bool":false},{"option":"Ascites","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hemorrhoids","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the tumors of the gall bladder?","answers":[{"option":"They occur more commonly in males","bool":false},{"option":"They usually metastasize to spine","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell type of the cancer is the most common","bool":false},{"option":"90% are diagnosed pre-operatively","bool":false},{"option":"Infiltrative form of gall bladder cancers is more common","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a non-epithelioid gastric tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Papilloma","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 3-month-old child has acute diarrhea and is irritable. When his skin is pinched it goes down slowly. His mucosal membranes are also seen to be dry. What is the appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Oral rehydration solution 300 ml every 4 hours","bool":true},{"option":"Normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"Ringers solution and metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Oral rehydration solution 50-60 mg after watery diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Dextrose solution and metronidazole","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 3-month-old child has acute diarrhea and is irritable. When his skin is pinched it goes down slowly. His mucosal membranes are also seen to be dry. Which of the following corresponds to the condition of this child?","answers":[{"option":"The child is not dehydrated","bool":false},{"option":"Severe dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Mild dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Moderate dehydration","bool":true},{"option":"Hypovolemia","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of acute gastroenteritis in children less than 1 year in age?","answers":[{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is characterized by profuse, non-bilious vomiting after feeding?","answers":[{"option":"Pyloric stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Hirschsprung  disease","bool":false},{"option":"Necrotizing  enterocolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Malrotation and volvulus","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 6-year-old child presents with lethargy, unconsciousness, and an acidotic breath. Which of the following tests would be appropriate in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Blood sugar level","bool":true},{"option":"Renal function test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function test","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with heavy breathing and convulsions. His blood sugar level is 400 mg/dL. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetic ketoacidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Salicylate toxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"An infant presents with cherry-red spots on the macula. He has had progressive loss of developmental milestones and shows signs of mental retardation. Which of the following investigations should be done?","answers":[{"option":"Liver function test","bool":false},{"option":"Serum ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Liver biopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"The 5-year-old child is having episodes of convulsions. On examination hepatosplenomegaly, and abdominal distention is observed. A blood sugar test reveals hypoglycemia. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Niemann pick disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary galactokinase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Pompe disease","bool":false},{"option":"McArdle disease","bool":false},{"option":"Von Gierke disease","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is used in combination with adefovir dipivoxil to prevent resistance?","answers":[{"option":"Ribavirin","bool":false},{"option":"Afavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Emtricitabine","bool":false},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of adefovir dipivoxil?","answers":[{"option":"Guanosine analog","bool":false},{"option":"Cytidine analog","bool":false},{"option":"DNA polymerase Inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor (NRTI)","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleoside analog","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Metoclopramide and domperidone are dopamine antagonists. Which of the following is not seen with domperidone?","answers":[{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":false},{"option":"Galactorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Tardive dyskinesia","bool":true},{"option":"Impotence","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is deficient in a person taking proton-pump inhibitors?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is used for heartburn and lowers acid secretion by blocking H2 receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Sucralfate","bool":false},{"option":"Octreotide","bool":false},{"option":"Cimetidine","bool":true},{"option":"Omeprazole","bool":false},{"option":"Misoprostol","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Patients being given cimetidine should be warned regarding which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":true},{"option":"Increased libido","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs prevents acid secretion by irreversibly binding to H+/K+ ATPase receptors?","answers":[{"option":"Misoprostol","bool":false},{"option":"Aluminium hydroxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nizatidine","bool":false},{"option":"Omeprazole","bool":true},{"option":"Octreotide","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the correct mechanism of action of methylxanthines?","answers":[{"option":"Negative chronotropic and inotropic effects","bool":false},{"option":"Increased gastric acid secretion","bool":true},{"option":"Central nervous system depression","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary retention","bool":false},{"option":"Increased bronchoconstriction","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the first-line treatment of acute variceal bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"Subcutaneous octreotide","bool":false},{"option":"Blood transfusion","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous terlipressin","bool":true},{"option":"Broad-spectrum antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is used to treat a Helicobacter pylori infection?","answers":[{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Clarithromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the route of transmission of the hepatitis E virus (HEV)?","answers":[{"option":"Perinatal route","bool":false},{"option":"Fecal-oral route","bool":true},{"option":"Parenteral route","bool":false},{"option":"Blood-borne route","bool":false},{"option":"Sexual route","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A 37-year-old male patient is being tested. His reports show HBsAg=-ve, anti-HBs=-ve, anti-HBe=-ve, HBeAg=-ve, and anti-HBc=IgM reactive. Which of the following corresponds to this patient's results?","answers":[{"option":"Recovery from hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Incubatory period","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccination","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hepatitis B","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic with low virulence","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following organisms causes enterocolitis associated with Reiter’s syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella dysenteriae","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a spiral-shaped organism?","answers":[{"option":"Bacillus anthracis","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcina ventriculi","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What is the incubation period of the hepatitis A virus?","answers":[{"option":"8 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"14 days","bool":false},{"option":"6 days","bool":false},{"option":"6 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"4 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"The endoscopy of a patient reveals an ulcerated mass on the antrum. A biopsy sample is sent and confirmed to be an adenocarcinoma. What is the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Total gastrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Subtotal gastrectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Drainage","bool":false},{"option":"Radical gastrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Wedge resection","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is the appropriate intervention for a peptic ulcer with duodenal perforation?","answers":[{"option":"Sleeve gastrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Reichel–Polya operation","bool":false},{"option":"Bilroth II","bool":false},{"option":"Keep omental patch and suture the defect","bool":true},{"option":"Bilroth I","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What causes post-operative paralytic ileus?","answers":[{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Uremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Saturated fatty acids increase the risk of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiovascular disease","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal ulcers","bool":false},{"option":"Steatorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Gastric carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the glycemic index?","answers":[{"option":"The ability of food to increase blood glucose levels","bool":true},{"option":"The ability of food to reduce blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of the liver to reduce blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of the liver to maintain blood glucose levels","bool":false},{"option":"The ability of the liver to increase blood glucose levels","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the purpose of nutritional assessment?","answers":[{"option":"To assess the ratio of malnourished people","bool":true},{"option":"To assess the disease burden in a population","bool":false},{"option":"To assess the ratio of obese people","bool":false},{"option":"To assess the ratio of anemic people","bool":false},{"option":"To assess the ratio of economically disadvantaged people","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic X-ray finding of jejunal obstruction?","answers":[{"option":"Air under diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Valvulae conniventes","bool":true},{"option":"Thumbprinting sign","bool":false},{"option":"String of pearl appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Stepladder sign","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following represents the distribution of sex and age of a population?","answers":[{"option":"Population growth","bool":false},{"option":"Population dynamic","bool":false},{"option":"Population momentum","bool":false},{"option":"Population pyramid","bool":true},{"option":"Population distribution","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following terms describes why population growth does not stop even after the fertility rate declines?","answers":[{"option":"Population dynamics","bool":false},{"option":"Population distribution","bool":false},{"option":"Population momentum","bool":true},{"option":"Population pyramid","bool":false},{"option":"Population growth","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Raindrop pigmentation and hyperkeratosis are characteristic findings of which poison?","answers":[{"option":"Lead","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":true},{"option":"Zinc","bool":false},{"option":"Mercury","bool":false},{"option":"Copper","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Hemorrhagic gastroenteritis, acute tubular necrosis, and shock are seen in which of the following toxicities?","answers":[{"option":"Thallium","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false},{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphorus","bool":false},{"option":"Mercury","bool":true}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A road rash is classified as which type of injury?","answers":[{"option":"Scratch abrasion","bool":false},{"option":"Imprint abrasion","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure abrasion","bool":false},{"option":"Graze abrasion","bool":true},{"option":"Linear abrasion","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"A friction burn is which type of injury?","answers":[{"option":"Chop wound","bool":false},{"option":"Contusion","bool":false},{"option":"Laceration","bool":false},{"option":"Abrasion","bool":true},{"option":"Slash wound","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following terms measures a woman's physiological ability to bear and deliver children?","answers":[{"option":"Total fertility","bool":false},{"option":"Fecundity","bool":true},{"option":"Infertility","bool":false},{"option":"Fertility","bool":false},{"option":"Subfertility","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a chemical asphyxiant?","answers":[{"option":"Nitric oxide gas","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide gas","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrogen dioxide gas","bool":false},{"option":"Mustard gas","bool":false},{"option":"Phosgene gas","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a convex-shaped hemorrhage when seen on brain imaging?","answers":[{"option":"Intraparenchymal hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Extradural hemorrhage","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Pugilistic attitude is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Self defense","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue decomposition","bool":false},{"option":"Rigor mortis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation of muscle proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Livor mortis","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is the surest sign of death from starvation?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal epithelial dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Distended gallbladder","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophied liver","bool":false},{"option":"Marked emaciation","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue paper intestine","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following terms is used for a state of extreme emaciation?","answers":[{"option":"Malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Malabsorption","bool":false},{"option":"Kwashiorkor","bool":false},{"option":"Marasmus","bool":true},{"option":"Muscle wasting","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"What color precipitate is formed after adding 3% tannic acid to blood samples containing carboxyhemoglobin?","answers":[{"option":"Purple","bool":false},{"option":"Pink","bool":true},{"option":"White","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Cherry red","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is a sign of death that occurred due to antemortem burns?","answers":[{"option":"Peeling of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Pugilistic attitude","bool":false},{"option":"Crocodile-skin","bool":false},{"option":"Degloving sign","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxyhemoglobin presence","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is the correct color and its respective duration in a black eye?","answers":[{"option":"Livid red 3rd day","bool":false},{"option":"Green 2nd day","bool":false},{"option":"Blue-black 2nd day","bool":false},{"option":"Violet 5th day","bool":false},{"option":"Red 1st day","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/gastrointestinal/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of infections post-splenectomy?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr